<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 15:01:35 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://calebmallen.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Desmond, Peanuts &amp; Anna | 10</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/desmond-peanuts-anna/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/desmond-peanuts-anna/</guid>
      <description>Not my favorite group of books but absolutely loved Disappearing Desmond, if you get a chance it is a must read!
Peanut by Linas Alsenas
Published 2007. Simple and fun artwork and I enjoyed the story. It could have given us some perspective on the elephant. Still, the premise was silly; I did not care for the ending as much since Mildred had no character change, but overall it was a fun and silly read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sassy Miss Nelson | 09</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/sassy-miss-nelson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/sassy-miss-nelson/</guid>
      <description>Dragon and Captain Written by P.R. Allabach, illustrated by Lucas Turnbloom
Published 2015. The artwork isn’t to my taste, but it is done well. The book is also laid out like a graphic novel, so it’s like a child’s first visual novel experience, which is neat. The visual novel style has been quite prominent in recent years. Watching it bleed into picture books and other ranges/types of books has been interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun with Photographs | 08</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/fun-with-photographs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/fun-with-photographs/</guid>
      <description>An interesting week of books, first time we encounter a book with photographs as opposed to illustrations. Also, if you have read any of these books, feel free to leave a comment of your thoughts as well.
Sheep, Sheep, Sheep, Help Me Fall Asleep By Arlene Alda
Published 1992. No drawings in this book but very silly and fun images. The story is written with great flow. Every line is easy to read and pairs with the next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gnarly Five Books | 07</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/gnarly-five-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/gnarly-five-books/</guid>
      <description>A great collection of books this week. I really loved the artwork for Surf’s Up, and On A Magical Do-Nothing Day.
On a Magical Do-Nothing Day by Beatrice Alemagna
Published initially in 2016 in France, 2017, USA. The first spread immediately gets me interested and invested, with its tone and telling ‘just enough.’ The artwork is phenomenal, with incredible depth from ‘sad’ colors and great emotion to go with the words.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Louella Mae &amp; Jez Alborough | 06</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/louella-mae-and-alborough/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/louella-mae-and-alborough/</guid>
      <description>When a majority of the weeks books a from one author I like to research them a little bit, so here is the Candlewick Profile for Jez Alborough. I really enjoyed what he said about ideas:
Ideas are like butterflies. If I chase them, they will get away. But if I sit perfectly still, and I’m lucky, one might land with a tickle on my open hand. Then I just look as the butterfly opens up its wings like the pages of a book, and I think: “Aha!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Longer Text with Allan Ahlberg | 05</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/longer-text-ahlberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/longer-text-ahlberg/</guid>
      <description>I remember my family reading me Allan Ahlberg books when a child, and I can certainly say I still enjoy his writing today. While reading his 3 books from the selection this week, I went on a google journey and found this interesting read on Mr. Ahlberg.
It was a Dark and Stormy Night by Janet &amp;amp; Allan Ahlberg
1993, Immediately enjoy the artwork, was very nostalgic for me and I am always sucker for some nice drop caps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jon Agee x Five | 04</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/jon-agee-times-five/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/jon-agee-times-five/</guid>
      <description>Dmitri the Astronaut by Jon Agee &amp;ldquo;It was just before dawn when Dmitri touched down in the Atlantic Ocean.&amp;rdquo;
A quick read that left me wanting more. Sweet message that could’ve been punched up some with more story for a bigger impact for the theme of the story, about how only the opinions that we have friendship and connection with are the ones that we should treasure most. It’s not about a stranger’s ‘love’ and ‘admiration’ but those that we are connected with in friendship and connection in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Families and Dog Pigs | 3</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/families-and-dog-pigs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/families-and-dog-pigs/</guid>
      <description>Norman Speak! by Caroline Anderson &amp;amp; Qin Leng &amp;ldquo;We went to the animal shelter”
Quite wordy of a story and there wasn’t much conflict in a traditional sense, but there was still a problem, was enjoyable. I like what the story is attempting to say or the intended message on perception and judging things before we can understand as well as the love and things we do for love; but I felt at times it needed just a little big extra to keep attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Ged&#39;s and a Rabbit | 02</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/three-geds-and-a-rabbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/three-geds-and-a-rabbit/</guid>
      <description>Dear Peter Rabbit by Alma Flor Ada, pictures by Leslie Tryon &amp;ldquo;Have I got news for you.&amp;rdquo;
I liked the layout of the spreads with each page having a letter from one of the characters, but the story overall was ‘lost’ and quite wordy with details I really didn’t care about and unnecessary in my opinion. It’s obvious very quickly that these characters are from Goldilocks and the Three Bears, Peter Rabbit, and The Three Little Pigs, as the text spends a little too much time on talking about those stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duck, Elephant and Lil Ki-Pat | 01</title>
      <link>http://calebmallen.com/posts/duck-elephand-and-kipat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 15:01:35 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://calebmallen.com/posts/duck-elephand-and-kipat/</guid>
      <description>Bringing the Rains to Kapiti Plain by Verna Aardema, pictures by Beatriz Vidal &amp;ldquo;This is the great Kapita Plain”
I was already familiar with this book, I remember my 1st or 2nd grade teacher reading this to us, as well as this being a book that was a part of the Reading Program at our Elementary School, where we could read books and take quizzes to gain points. This book has a very strong rhythm and repetitious writing to it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
